<resources>
    <string name="app_name">FaleHafiz</string>
    <string name="get_a_poem">get a poem</string>
    <string name="about">about</string>
    <string name="no_poem_selected">no poem selected</string>
    <string name="poem">O Saki! Pass around and oﬀer the wine cup, for;
Love which seemed easy at ﬁrst is an uneasy lore.
The breeze made her tress waft the scent of a musk skin; The musky curls of her black tress wore many hearts thin. How can I feel safe and secure in the Beloved’s abode? For the bell cries: “Bind up your bundles! Take the road!” In wine, dye your prayer mat if the Magian Master says; For, the Traveler alone is privy to the secrets of the Ways. The night dark, the waves dreadful, the whirlpools roar; Do they know our state, the light-burdened on the shore? I followed my fancy; ill fame was all my lot;
How can it be a secret when oﬀ my chest it’s cut?
Haﬁz! If you seek the beloved’s presence, stay anear; Relinquish worldly ways when you ﬁnd one so dear.</string>
    <string name="poem2">O you whose radiant face is reﬂected by the moon;
The dimple in your chin is to loveliness a boon. Hankering for your sight, my spirit leaps to my throat; Shall it return or leave? What is the bid to be sought? The vision of your narcissus eyes left none but in blight: Better for you to veil the purity of your engaging sight! Our Fortune sunk in sleep may ﬁnally come to awaken; Poured over her eyes is water from your charm taken. Send with the breeze a posy from your face so fair:
So I may pick a scent from your garden’s dust to share! God give you longevity and success, Sakis of Jam’s court, Even though, I was denied a wine-cup with you to sport. My heart is sorely troubled; let the lover know:
O friends, beware lest my spirit may perish in woe.
O Lord! I wonder when my love is fated to ensnare,
That ruﬄed-haired maiden with my serene soul to pair. Pass by with your skirt uplifted to shun blood and dust: Oh, this path has witnessed a throng despaired and lost. Haﬁz is praying. Hear! Say Amen! Say!
Let your ruby lips on mine my food lay!
O breeze! Convey to the people of Yazd what we say: May the head of every ingrate to a mall bat fall prey! Though distant I may seem to be from your seat:
Your king I magnify and your soul I deify at your feet.
O Lofty King! For God’s sake, let my desire be met: May I kiss like a star the dust where your feet are set</string>
    <string name="poem3">Should that charming Turk of Shiraz win my soul, Samarkand and Bukhara, I will barter for her mole. Saki! Serve the remnant wine; in Eden, you cannot gaze Upon the barges of Ruknabad or Musalla balmy ways. Alas! The saucy sweet dames plunge the town in broil; Lo, they murdered patience as Turks had trays of spoil. The beloved is needless of an imperfect love like mine; By light, colors and mole, can a face more fairly shine? From the beauty of Josef increasing daily without fail, I knew love could lure Zuleika from behind the veil. Aﬀront me or curse me, I will pray; it’s meet;
A bitter reply suits those ruby lips sugar-sweet.
Love! Hear my advice! For the youths gay,
Cherish – dearer than life – what wise men say: “Partake of music and wine! Care little how time ﬂies Nay, no one has ever resolved the secret of the skies.”
Your lays versed; pearls pierced. Haﬁz! Sing in bliss! Let the sky grace my poetry with clusters of Pleiades.</string>
    <string name="poem4">Should that charming Turk of Shiraz win my soul, Samarkand and Bukhara, I will barter for her mole. Saki! Serve the remnant wine; in Eden, you cannot gaze Upon the barges of Ruknabad or Musalla balmy ways. Alas! The saucy sweet dames plunge the town in broil; Lo, they murdered patience as Turks had trays of spoil. The beloved is needless of an imperfect love like mine; By light, colors and mole, can a face more fairly shine? From the beauty of Josef increasing daily without fail, I knew love could lure Zuleika from behind the veil. Aﬀront me or curse me, I will pray; it’s meet;
A bitter reply suits those ruby lips sugar-sweet.
Love! Hear my advice! For the youths gay,
Cherish – dearer than life – what wise men say: “Partake of music and wine! Care little how time ﬂies Nay, no one has ever resolved the secret of the skies.”
Your lays versed; pearls pierced. Haﬁz! Sing in bliss! Let the sky grace my poetry with clusters of Pleiades.</string>
    <string name="poem5">Last night, from temple to tavern, our Elder went, Comrades of the Path! “What advice can be to us lent?” How can we, the disciples, to the qibla make our way, When the Master turned to where the tavern lay?”
In the Magian’s tavern, we too will our sojourn make: Our fate led us from primordiality to the path we take. Could the mind see what joy the heart in love did gain, Wise men would lose mind to be captivated in our chain. Your beaming face revealed to us from above a sign: Grace and goodness are now destined to combine.
Deep in the night, will your stony heart to softness turn, For our ﬁery sighs? And can grief our breasts burn?
Haﬁz! Silent! Our sighs’ arrows pierce the sphere, Have pity on your soul! Our missiles, avoid and fear!</string>
    <string name="aboutInf">version 1
    created by Mahdi Afarideh</string>
    <string name="selected_poem">no poem selected</string>


</resources>